Secret Clearance

■ malcolm.t129@gmail.com ☐ +443 801 3973

■ Baltimore, MD ■ Malcolm Thompson

| Skills |
|-----------------|
| Python |
| Java |
| C++ |
| Git |
| Linux |
| LaTeX |
| JavaScript/ES6+ |
| Solidity |

AWS

Projects

CryptoCurrency Speculative Trading App

GitHub Link

Crypto & Blockchain, Professor Jal

Served as team lead for the development of a cryptocurrency speculative trading application that shows current price action and which strategies may prove to be profitable, if implemented through my teams smart contract.

Designed the database schema and structured the backend to properly query and serve the appropriate data to the frontend based on user specification.

Church of Philippi Inventory Management

GitHub link

Software Engineering, Dr. Song

Using Angular for frontend, Nest.js for backend and PostgreSQL for the database, my team designed and created an online database to track inventory of a local church.

The project was deployed using AWS services (S3, EC2 and RDS instances) to make accessible for staff of the church.

Work Experience

Sensor & Systems Technician

Jul 2018 - Present

Northrop Grumman

Identified faults down to the circuit card and stress and function tested over 2000 units of five different modular communication systems, in order to ensure the units were in specifications that our customers required.

Wrote technical reports and develop charts/graphs, and schematics to illustrate equipment operating characteristics, malfunctions and deviations from design specifications in order to improve overall purposefulness of systems to the company.

Ground Radio Repairman

Aug 2013 - Jun 2018

USMC(Sergeant)

Maintained a TS/SCI security clearance.

Repaired over 250 individual radio equipment as necessary, using electronic test equipment, hand tools, and power tools.

Assumed the position of Quality Control officer to ensure all systems inducted into maintenance were returned in good order and met all specifications, directed by Headquarters, before leaving maintenance sections.

Education

BSc in Computer Science

Towson University

Jan 2021 - May 2023

GPA: 3.6